sched.org 2019-11-09

# Privacy Policy - Sched

Sched LLC (“Sched”, “us”, “we”, or “our”) takes the privacy and security of your personal data seriously. This Privacy Policy describes how we protect and use the personal data we collect about you through our website and in connection with the services we offer (“Service”).

Please contact [support@sched.com](mailto:support@sched.com) with any requests, questions, or concerns relating to this Privacy Policy.

## 1\. Collection of Information.

We collect and process personal data from you only for lawful reasons, such as our legitimate interests, your consent, or to fulfill our legal or contractual obligations. We collect and use the following types of data from you:

(a) Personal Account Information. The information that we collect about you includes any information that you choose to provide to us in any form, including but not limited to, through e-mail messages, forms, surveys, or the registration process. This may include your name, physical mailing address, e-mail address, telephone number, and payment or financial information. We also collect information that others choose to provide to us about you, such as when event organizers add your name, company, position, location, photo and biographical information into their event.

**How do we collect data?** Your personal data is usually gathered from two places:

1) When event organizers invite you to use the Sched application and pre-fill some data about you including your name, email, company and position.

2) When you create your own account on Sched and fill out your profile so that other attendees can find you in the directory.

(b) Usage and Services. We collect any files, content and information that you share with us through your use of our Services. We also collect information from and about the devices you use to access our Services such as the dates and times of your visit to our website and use of our Services, IP addresses, the types of browser, operating systems and languages you use, the pages on our website that you visit and the identity of the web page you visited before coming to our website. The device you use to access our Services may also transmit location information to us.

**Why do we collect data?** The data we collect about your usage, which pages you visit and what devices you are using helps us improve our Services. We can use this information to fix bugs and identify which parts of the Services need to be improved.

## 2\. How We Use Your Information.

We may use your personal data as follows:

**Customer Service and Communications.** We may use your information in connection with the purpose for which it was provided. For instance, if you contact us by e-mail, we will use the data you provide to answer your question or resolve your problem and will respond to the email address from which the contact came.

**Use of and Access to the Services.** We will use your data to provide you with access to or use of the Services or functionality and to analyze your use of such Services or functionality. For instance, if you supply data relating to your identity or qualifications to use certain portions of the Services, we will use that information to make a decision as to granting you access to use such Services and to assess your ongoing qualification to use such Services.

**Internal Operations.** We may use your personal data for internal business purposes, including without limitation, to help us improve the content and functionality of the Services, to better understand our customers and users of the Service, to improve the Services, to protect against, identify or address wrongdoing, to enforce our Terms of Service, to manage your account and provide you with customer service, and to generally manage the Services and our business.

**Event Organizers.** We allow event organizers to use our email tools to contact you regarding your current and past events, so you may receive emails from our system that originate with event organizers and that we send on their behalf. If you registered for an event on the Services, your email address is available to that event organizer. However, organizers may also import the email addresses they have from external sources and send communications through the Services to those email addresses, and we will deliver those communications to those email addresses on the organizer’s behalf. The organizer and not Sched is responsible for sending these emails. You can opt out of these here <http://sched.com/unsubscribe>.

If we intend to use any personal data in any manner that is not consistent with this Privacy Policy, you will be informed of such anticipated use prior to or at the time the personal data is collected.

## 3\. How Information is Shared.

We may share your personal data with third parties to help us provide the Services and for our internal operations. We may also disclose your information to third parties if we determine that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with the law; (b) protect any person from death or serious bodily injury; (c) prevent fraud or abuse of our Services or our users; or (d) protect our property rights.

We do not sell, license, lease or otherwise disclose your information except as described in this Privacy Policy.

We share your personal data with the following third parties:

## SOCIAL

**Facebook:** For account creation and social networking. Facebook Connect lets attendees easily create a new account and import their photo and company information. We also use this connection to show them friends that are attending the same event.

**Twitter:** For social networking. Twitter Connect lets attendees pull in their profile info (location, site, photo) and save time filling out yet another social profile. We also pull their contacts and show them friends that are attending the same event.

**LinkedIn:** For social networking. LinkedIn Connect lets attendees pull in their profile info (location, site, photo) and save time filling out yet another social profile. We also pull their contacts and show them friends that are attending the same event.

**Foursquare:** For social networking. Foursquare Connect lets attendees pull their contacts and show them friends that are attending the same event.

## ANALYTICS

**Google LLC (Google Analytics):** For tracking analytics and usage. This helps us learn from trends.

**Visual Website Optimizer:** For A/B testing. We use VWO (Visual Website Optimizer) to improve the effectiveness of our site and application. For example, perhaps removing a field from the signup form will help more people create new event sites.

**Mouseflow:** For tracking how users interact with a page. This helps us improve the user experience and fix bugs.

**Google LLC (Firebase):** For tracking analytics and usage of mobile apps. This helps us learn from trends and fix errors.

## INFRASTRUCTURE

**Amazon Web Services:** For hosting and serving files using their content delivery network.

**Cloudflare:** For hosting and serving files using their content delivery network.

**Eventbrite:** For integrating Eventbrite events into Sched, including attendee data and registration info.

**Google LLC (Google G-Suite):** For team calendars, email, document hosting, conference calls and other business tools to enable communication and collaboration internally.

**New Relic:** For tracking server statistics like loading and response times. This helps us improve our application.

**Recurly:** For billing. We use Recurly to securely store billing information and charge for both one-time services and recurring charges.

**The Rocket Science Group, LLC dba MailChimp (Mandrill):** For email. We use Mandrill (owned by MailChimp) to power all of the emails that Sched sends out on behalf of our company and the event organizers that use Sched. They help ensure that organizers are sending email to people that want it, and not spamming them.

## SUPPORT & SALES TOOLS

**Calendly:** For scheduling support and sales calls with potential and current customers.

**Intercom:** For support. We use Intercom to power the chat widgets throughout the application. Attendees and organizers can use these to email or live-chat with our support team. We send additional data into Intercom, like which plan you have, to help us prioritize messages and improve our application.

**Pipedrive:** For tracking potential customers and their decision making when interacting with our sales team.

**Slack:** For tracking potential customers and their decision making when interacting with our sales team.

**Basecamp:** For tracking potential customers and their decision making when interacting with our sales team.

## 4\. International Transfers and Privacy Shield

Because Sched and its servers are located in the United States, we necessarily transfer any data that is collected from outside the United States to the United States for processing and storage.

Sched complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. Sched has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and data subject rights under the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to [view our certification page](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt00000008WVNAA2&status=Active), please visit [privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)

The U.S. Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over Sched’s compliance with the Privacy Shield Frameworks. In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including in order to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Sched’s accountability for personal data that it receives in the United States under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Sched remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Sched proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Sched commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. European Union and Swiss individuals with Privacy Shield inquiries or complaints should first contact Sched by email at support@sched.com or via post at:

Sched LLC Privacy Officer  
8605 Santa Monica Blvd #69687  
Los Angeles, CA 90069

Sched has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers](http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers) for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you.

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at [privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction)

## 5\. Protection and Storage.

We strive to keep your information secure and use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that we do so. We have made significant investments in protecting and safeguarding your information. We continuously upgrade and enhance our security measures as new tools, techniques and technology become available. However, we cannot and do not promise, represent, warrant or guaranty that your information or any information about you will not be accessed by third parties or misused by them in spite of our security efforts.

We retain your data and information that you provide (or that is provided about you) in connection with our Services for as long as we need it to provide you the Services.

## 6\. Your Rights

If you live in the EU, European Economic Area (“EEA”), United Kingdom (“UK”) you have certain rights regarding your personal data, including:

• You may request access to your personal data and obtain information about our processing of your personal data, with whom we share your personal data, and your rights.

• You may request that we restrict our processing of your personal data.

• You may object to our processing of your personal data.

• Where we process personal data based on your consent, you may withdraw your consent.

• You may correct personal data that is inaccurate and have incomplete personal data completed.

• You may request that we delete your account and personal data or return or provide a copy of your personal data to you. However, we may retain certain information to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, or enforce our agreements, and there may be some delay in deleting certain data from our servers and back-up storage.

To submit a question or concern about your rights, please email [support@sched.com](mailto:support@sched.com).

**Exporting Your Data**

To request an export of your personal data, please email [support@sched.com](mailto:support@sched.com) with the subject line “GDPR Export”.

If you need further assistance regarding your rights, please contact us using the contact information provided below and we will consider your request in accordance with applicable law. In some cases our ability to uphold these rights for you may depend upon our obligations to process personal information for security, safety, fraud prevention reasons, compliance with regulatory or legal requirements, or because processing is necessary to deliver the services you have requested. Where this is the case, we will inform you of specific details in response to your request. If you live in the EEA, UK, or Switzerland, and you are unsatisfied with our response, you have the right to lodge a complaint regarding your personal data with an applicable supervisory authority.

## 7\. Choice/Opt-out.

If we ever send you information by e-mail concerning new products, services or information that you did not expressly request, we will provide you with an e-mail address by which you may request no further notices.

## 8\. Cookies.

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. We use cookies to help us identify and track visitors, their usage of our Services, and their preferences. Visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using our Services, with the drawback that certain features of our Services may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

## 9\. Links to Third Party Sites.

This Privacy Policy only applies to information we receive. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Sched does not own or control, or employees that Sched does not manage. Our Services furnish links to third party websites. Any information you provide to, or that is collected by, third-party sites may be subject to the privacy policies of those sites, if any. You should read the privacy policies of any third-party sites you visit.

## 10\. No Collection of Children’s Personal Information.

Our Services are intended for general audiences and commercial use and are not intended for and may not be used by children under the age of 13, or any higher minimum age in the jurisdiction where the person resides. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13, or any higher minimum age in the jurisdiction where the person resides, and take reasonable steps to delete any information we believe to be in violation of this provision.

## 11\. Changes and Contact Information.

If we modify this Privacy Policy, we will post the updated version on our website. It is your responsibility to periodically review this Privacy Policy, and you are bound by any changes to it by using our Services or websites after such changes have been posted.

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or your rights, please email [support@sched.com](mailto:support@sched.com) or contact us at Sched LLC / 8605 Santa Monica Blvd #69687 / Los Angeles, CA 90069-4109.

Last updated on July 21, 2018

Have questions? Contact us at [support@sched.com](mailto:support@sched.com).
